<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Splash</string>
    <string name="open">Open</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>

    <string name="university">Ahsanullah University Of Science and Technology</string>
    <string name="department">Computer Science and Engineering</string>

    <string-array name="abbreviations_list_header">
        <item>API</item>
        <item>ALU</item>
        <item>ASCII</item>
        <item>AAC</item>
        <item>BIU</item>
        <item>BCD</item>
        <item>BASIC</item>
        <item>BIOS</item>
        <item>CC</item>
        <item>CAI</item>
        <item>CAD</item>
        <item>CSS</item>
        <item>CPI</item>
        <item>DPI</item>
        <item>DVR</item>
        <item>EDI</item>
        <item>GUI</item>
        <item>HTTP</item>
        <item>IP</item>
        <item>JDK</item>
        <item>JVM</item>
        <item>JRE</item>
        <item>URL</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="abbreviations_list_child">

        <item>
            Application Programming Interface
            \n\nIn Computer Programming,an application programming interface is a set of subroutine,definitions,protocols and tools for building application software.
        </item>

        <item name ="ALU">
            Arithmetic Logic Unit
            \n\nAn arithmetic logic unit is a combinational digital electronic circuit that performs arithmetic and bitwise operations on integer binary numbers.
        </item>

      <item>
            American Standard Code for Information Interchange
            \n\nASCII is a character encoding standard for electronic.
       </item>

        <item>
            Advanced Audio Coding
            \n\nAdvanced Audio Coding is a proprietary audio coding standard for lossy digital audio compression.
        </item>

        <item name="BIU">
            Bus Interface Unit
            \n\nThe BIU provides various functions,including generation of the memory and I O addresses for the transfer of data between outside the CPU and the EU.
        </item>

        <item name="BCD">
            Binary Coded Decimal
            \n\nIn computing and electronic systems,binary coded decimal is a class of binary encodings of decimal numbers where each decimal digit is represented by a fixed number of bits,usually four or eight.
        </item>

        <item name="BASIC">
           High level programming language
            \n\nBASIC is a family of general purpose,high level programming languages whose design philosophy emphasizes ease of use.
        </item>

        <item name="BIOS">
            Basic Input Output system
            \n\nFor IBM PC compatible computers,BIOS is non volatile firmware used to perform hardware initialization during the booting process and to provide runtime services for operating systems and programs.
        </item>

        <item name="CC">
           Carbon Copy
            \n\nCarbon Copy is an email that is copied to one or more recipients.
        </item>

        <item name = "CAI">
           Computer Assisted Instruction
            \n\nCAI is a program of instructional material presented by means of a computer or computer systems.
        </item>

        <item name = "CAD">
           Computer Aided Design
            \n\nCAD is the use of computer systems to aid in the creation,modification,analysis or optimization of a design.
        </item>

        <item name = "CSS">
           Cascading Style Sheets
            \n\nCSS is a style sheet language used designing the presentation of a document written in a markup language.
        </item>

        <item name = "CPI">
            Clock Cycles Per Instruction
            \n\nCPI is one aspect of a processors performance.The average number of clock cycles per instruction for a program or program fragment.
        </item>

        <item name = "DPI">
           Dots Per Inch
            \n\nDPI is a measure of spatial printing or video or image scanner dot density,in particular the number of individual dots that can be placed in a line within the span of 1 inch.
        </item>

        <item name = "DVR">
            Digital Video Recorder
            \n\nA digital video recorder is an electronic device that records video in a digital format to a disk drive,USB flash drive,SD memory card,SSD or other local or networked mass storage device.
        </item>

        <item name = "EDI">
            Electronic Data Interchange
            \n\nElectronic data interchange is the concept of businesses communicating electronically certain information that was traditionally communicated on paper.
        </item>



        <item name = "GUI">
            Graphical User Interface
            \n\nA graphical user interface is a human computer interface,a way for humans to interact with computers that uses windows,icons and menus.
        </item>


        <item name = "HTTP">
             Hypertext Transfer Protocol
            \n\nHTTP is an application protocol for distributed,collaborative and hypermedia in formation systems.
        </item>

        <item name = "IP">
            Internet Protocol address
            \n\nAn  Internet Protocol address is a numerical label assigned to each device connected to a computer network that uses the internet Protocol for communication.
        </item>

        <item name = "JDK">
            Java Development Kit
            \n\nThe  Java Development Kit is an implementation of either one of the Jave Platform,Standard Edition,Java Platform,Enterprise Edition,or Java Platform,Micro Edition plateforms released by oracle.
        </item>

        <item name = "JVM">
           Java Virtual Machine
            \n\nA Java Virtual Machine is an abstract computing system machine that enables a computer to run a Java program.
        </item>

        <item name = "JRE">
            Java Runtime Environment
            \n\nThe Java Runtime Environment is a set of software tools for development of Java applications a Runtime Environment.
        </item>

        <item name = "URL">
            Uniform Resource Locator
            \n\nUniform Resource Locator is a form of URL and is a standardized naming convention for addressing documents accessible over the Internet.
        </item>


    </string-array>

</resources>
